freepresets.com 2019-06-09

# Privacy Policy | Presetpro | Free Lightroom Presets, Luminar Presets, Photoshop Actions & More!

## **Privacy Policy**

This page informs you of our policies regarding the collection, use, and disclosure of personal data when you use our service and the choices you have associated with that data.

We use your data to provide and improve the Service. By using the Service, you agree to the collection and use of information in accordance with this policy. Unless otherwise defined in this Privacy Policy, terms used in this Privacy Policy have the same meanings as in our Terms and Conditions, accessible from https://www.presetpro.com

## Who we are

Presetpro.com and Freepresets.com, Presetpro Inc. Our website address: [https://www.presetpro.com](https://www.presetpro.com/) and [https://www.freepresets.com](https://www.freepresets.com/)

## What personal data we collect and why we collect it

### Cookies

To improve your experience on our site, we and our trusted third-party services that we use may use cookies and similar tracking technologies to track the activity on our service and hold certain information. We use cookies to help us measure the popularity of the site, different pages and visitor navigation so we can continue to improve and change the site based on usage.

Cookies are files with small amount of data which may include an anonymous unique identifier. Cookies are sent to your browser from a website and stored on your device. Tracking technologies from our third-party trusted services also may use beacons, tags, and scripts to collect and track information and to improve and analyze our Service.

You can instruct your browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. However, if you do not accept cookies, you may not be able to use some portions of our Service. You can opt out of Google Analytics if you disable or refuse the cookie, disable JavaScript, or use the [opt-out service provided by Google](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout)  or click here opt-out of Google Analytics To learn more about cookies and how to delete them from your browser [Click Here](https://www.aboutcookies.org/how-to-delete-cookies/)

### Comments

When visitors leave comments on the site we collect the data shown in the comments form, and also the visitor’s IP address and browser user agent string to help with spam detection.

An anonymized string created from your email address (also called a hash) may be provided to the Gravatar service to see if you are using it. The Gravatar service privacy policy is available here: <https://automattic.com/privacy/> After approval of your comment, your profile picture is visible to the public in the context of your comment

If you leave a comment on our site you may opt-in to saving your name, email address and website in cookies. These are for your convenience so that you do not have to fill in your details again when you leave another comment. These cookies will last for one year.

If you have an account and you log in to this site, we will set a temporary cookie to determine if your browser accepts cookies. This cookie contains no personal data and is discarded when you close your browser.

When you log in, we will also set up several cookies to save your login information and your screen display choices. Login cookies last for two days, and screen options cookies last for a year. If you select “Remember Me”, your login will persist for two weeks. If you log out of your account, the login cookies will be removed.

If you edit or publish an article, an additional cookie will be saved in your browser. This cookie includes no personal data and simply indicates the post ID of the article you just edited. It expires after 1 day.

### Media

If you upload images to the website, you should avoid uploading images with embedded location data (EXIF GPS) included. Visitors to the website can download and extract any location data from images on the website.

### Contact Forms

We use Ninja Forms for our contact page. Ninja Forms are WordPress form builders that allow us to easily customize email forms for this WordPress website. Ninja Forms collect your submitted information so that we can respond to your inquiry. We have turned off the “store submissions” option and we do not store your submissions. Click here to learn more about Ninja Forms’  [Privacy Policy](https://ninjaforms.com/privacy-policy/) and [Terms](https://ninjaforms.com/terms-conditions/).

### Email Subscription Lists

MailChimp – Our website uses MailChimp (The Rocket Science Group, LLC), as our automation platform to manage our email subscriber lists. MailChimp sends emails to our subscribers who double opt-in and consent to receive our weekly and monthly newsletters. Our newsletters consist of free presets and blog post updates. MailChimp uses cookies and other tracking technologies for technical reasons, performance reasons, and for functionality. You can opt-out of our subscription list at any time by clicking the unsubscribe link in the footer of any subscribed emails that you receive from us or by contacting us at [contact@presetpro.com](mailto:contact@presetpro.com). Click here to learn more about MailChimp’s [Privacy Policy](https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/) and [Terms](https://mailchimp.com/legal/terms/). To learn more about how MailChimp uses cookies and other tracking technologies [Click Here](https://mailchimp.com/legal/cookies/).

MailMunch – Our website also uses MailMunch. MailMunch provides us with professional email opt-in templates and forms so our users can easily subscribe to our newsletter. MailMunch integrates and with our MailChimp email subscriber list. To learn more about how MailMunch uses cookies and other tracking technologies [MailMunch’s privacy policy](https://legal.mailmunch.com/privacy/).

### FastSpring Ecommerce Engine

Our website partners with FastSpring for all payments and transactions. FastSpring is a service which makes products available for sale through an Ecommerce Engine. They do so as an independent e-commerce reseller of our products. FastSpring collects the Personal Data that you provide in connection with your purchase in order to enable your access to our products. FastSpring provides secure access to that data to us in order to fulfill obligations to you such as communication, registering purchases, after-sales services, technical support and for reporting purposes. We will not store or collect your payment card details. That information is provided directly to our third-party payment processors whose use of your personal information is governed by their Privacy Policy. To learn more about how FastSpring uses cookies and other tracking technologies [Click Here](https://fastspring.com/privacy/#cookies!loading).

By making a purchase through FastSpring Ecommerce Engine, you consent to the processing of data about you by FastSpring Ecommerce Engine in the manner described in FastSpring’s [Privacy Policy](https://fastspring.com/privacy/) and [Terms](https://fastspring.com/terms-use/).

### Embedded content from other websites

Articles on this site may include embedded content (e.g. videos, images, articles, etc.). Embedded content from other websites behaves in the exact same way as if the visitor has visited the other website.

These websites may collect data about you, use cookies, embed additional third-party tracking, and monitor your interaction with that embedded content, including tracking your interaction with the embedded content if you have an account and are logged in to that website. Your interactions with the embedded content and its features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

### Google Analytics

Our website uses Google Analytics, a service which transmits website traffic data to Google servers. We use reports provided by Google Analytics to help us understand our website traffic and webpage usage. Google Analytics uses “cookies”, which are text files placed on your computer, to help us analyze how users use the site. The information generated by the cookie about your use of the Website will normally be transmitted to and stored by Google on servers in the United States. We have set our Google Analytics account to retain personal data for the minimum period allowed, which is 14 months. To learn more about how Google Analytics uses cookies and other tracking technologies [Click Here](https://developers.google.com/analytics/devguides/collection/analyticsjs/cookie-usage).

By using this website, you consent to the processing of data about you by Google Analytics in the manner described in Google’s [Privacy Policy](https://policies.google.com/privacy) and [Terms](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/7108387) and for the purposes set out above. You can opt out of Google Analytics if you disable or refuse the cookie, disable JavaScript, or use the [opt-out service provided by Google](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout)  or click here opt-out of Google Analytics 

## Who we share your data with

### Social Media Sites, Widgets, Embedded Content and Plug-ins

Our website interfaces with social media sites, widgets, Embedded Content and plug-ins such as Facebook, Instagram, Pinterest, Twitter, Google Plus and others. If you are a member of a social media site, the interfaces may allow the social media site to connect your visits to this site with other Personal Information. If you choose to “like” or “share” information from this website through these services, you should review the privacy policy of that service. Your interactions with embedded content, social media sites, widgets, plug-ins and their features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

### Google Analytics

Our website uses Google Analytics, a service which transmits website traffic data to Google servers. We use reports provided by Google Analytics to help us understand our website traffic and webpage usage. By using this website, you consent to the processing of data about you by Google Analytics in the manner described in Google’s [Privacy Policy](https://policies.google.com/privacy) and [Terms](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/7108387) and for the purposes set out above. To learn more about how Google Analytics uses cookies and other tracking technologies [Click Here](https://developers.google.com/analytics/devguides/collection/analyticsjs/cookie-usage).

### FastSpring Ecommerce Engine

Our website uses FastSpring Ecommerce Engine for all payments and transactions. FastSpring is a service which makes products available for sale through an Ecommerce Engine. They do so as an independent e-commerce reseller of our products. FastSpring collects the Personal Data that you provide in connection with your purchase in order to enable your access to products. FastSpring provides secure access to that data to us in order to fulfill obligations to you such as communication, registering purchases, after-sales services, technical support and for reporting purposes. By making a purchase through FastSpring Ecommerce Engine, you consent to the processing of data about you by FastSpring Ecommerce Engine in the manner described in FastSpring’s [Privacy Policy](https://fastspring.com/privacy/) and [Terms](https://fastspring.com/terms-use/). To learn more about how FastSpring uses cookies and other tracking technologies [Click Here](https://fastspring.com/privacy/#cookies!loading).

### MailChimp

Our website uses MailChimp (The Rocket Science Group, LLC), as our automation platform to manage our email subscriber lists. MailChimp sends emails to our subscribers who double opt-in and consent to receive our weekly and monthly newsletters. MailChimp uses cookies and other tracking technologies for technical reasons, performance reasons, and for functionality. Click here to learn more about MailChimp’s [Privacy Policy](https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/) and [Terms](https://mailchimp.com/legal/terms/). To learn more about how MailChimp uses cookies and other tracking technologies [Click Here](https://mailchimp.com/legal/cookies/).

### MailMunch

Our website also uses MailMunch. MailMunch provides us with professional email opt-in templates and forms so our users can easily subscribe to our newsletter. MailMunch integrates and with our MailChimp email subscriber list. To learn more about how MailMunch uses cookies and other tracking technologies [MailMunch’s privacy policy](https://legal.mailmunch.com/privacy/).

## How long we retain your data

### Comments

If you leave a comment, the comment and its metadata are retained indefinitely. This is so we can recognize and approve any follow-up comments automatically instead of holding them in a moderation queue.

For users that register on our website (if any), we also store the personal information they provide in their user profile. All users can see, edit, or delete their personal information at any time (except they cannot change their username). Website administrators can also see and edit that information.

### Google Analytics

Our website uses Google Analytics, a service which transmits website traffic data to Google servers. We use reports provided by Google Analytics to help us understand website traffic and webpage usage. We have set our Google Analytics account to retain data for the minimum period allowed, which is 14 months. To learn more about Google Analytics check out their [Privacy Policy](https://policies.google.com/privacy) and [Terms](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/7108387).

### FastSpring Ecommerce Engine

Our website uses FastSpring Ecommerce Engine for all payments and transactions. When they collect or transmit personal data, they use industry-standard methods to protect that information.

Fast Spring retains Personal Data as follows:

Personal Data used for shipping and billing: 2 years after your last order

Payment Information: only for the duration of the payment

Personal Data used for marketing purposes: 3 years after the last contact with you (e.g. : request for information)

After these periods, FastSpring will delete the corresponding Personal Data. To learn more about FastSpring Ecommerce Engine check out their [Privacy Policy](https://fastspring.com/privacy/) and [Terms](https://fastspring.com/terms-use/).

### Email Subscriptions

Our website uses MailChimp (The Rocket Science Group, LLC), as our automation platform to manage our email subscriber lists. MailChimp sends emails to our subscribers who double opt-in and consent to receive our weekly and monthly newsletters. MailChimp uses cookies and other tracking technologies for technical reasons, performance reasons, and for functionality. To learn more about MailChimp’s data retention periods, [Click Here](https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/). To learn more about MailChimp check out their [Privacy Policy](https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/) and [Terms](https://mailchimp.com/legal/terms/). We remove subscribers that have not been active (opening emails within a 3 month period). You can opt-out of our subscription list at any time by clicking the unsubscribe link in the footer of any subscribed emails that you receive from us or by contacting us at [contact@presetpro.com](mailto:contact@presetpro.com).

## What rights you have over your data

If you have an account on this site, made a purchase, or have left comments, you can request to receive an exported file of the personal data we hold about you, including any data you have provided to us. You can also request that we erase any personal data we hold about you. This does not include any data we are obliged to keep for administrative, legal, or security purposes. If you have any questions regarding erasing any personal data that we hold about you please contact us at [contact@presetpro.com](mailto:contact@presetpro.com)

## How we protect your data

We use a secure server for our website. All supplied information is transmitted via Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology. Your payment information is processed through FastSpring Ecommerce Engine’s database which is only accessible by those authorized with special access rights to such systems. After a transaction, your private information will not be stored on our servers. Please see above for more information on FastSpring’s [Privacy Policy](https://fastspring.com/privacy/) and [Terms](https://fastspring.com/terms-use/).

We do not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer to outside parties your personally identifiable information. This does not include the trusted third parties mentioned above who assist us in operating our website, conducting our business, or servicing you. We may also release your information when we believe release is appropriate to comply with the law, enforce our site policies, or protect ours or others’ rights, property, or safety.

## Breach Notification

If we are made aware of any data breaches we will report this information to the relevant authorities within 72 hours. We will also inform the individuals who have been impacted by the breach.

## Changes to our Privacy Policy

We reserve the right to make changes to this privacy policy without notice. If we make any changes to our privacy policy, we will post those changes on this page.

## Our Contact Information

If there are any questions regarding this privacy policy please contact us at [contact@presetpro.com](mailto:contact@presetpro.com)
